Vishnu S

+91- 90801 97960 | vishnuskalai21@gmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/vishnu-shanmugam | https://github.com/Vishnushanmugam | https://vishnushanmugam.github.io/Portfolio/

Career Objective

To land a challenging job in a reputable company so I may broaden my knowledge, skills, and learnings. Obtain a responsible career path that will allow me to make the most of my education and experience while significantly contributing to the organization's growth.

Accomplishment

Participated in Department Level Hackathon Program in 2023 and won second place.

Education

CMS College of Science and Commerce

Coimbatore,

Post Graduation in Master of Computer Application

Aug 2022 – April 2024

CMS College of Science and Commerce

Coimbatore, Jun 2019 – May 2022

Graduation in Information Technology

Experience

Smartinternz, Telangana

Dec 2023 – Feb 2024

Software Test Automation

- Successfully completed a comprehensive software test automation internship, gaining hands-on experience in automating test cases using Katalon Studio.
- Developed proficiency in creating and executing automated test scripts for amazon & cura healthcare to ensure software quality and efficiency.

Bata Feb 2022 – Sept 2023

Sales Executive

- Consistently exceeding sales targets 100%, successfully operated in a dynamic retail environment, contributing to the overall revenue growth.
- Demonstrated exceptional customer service skills, assisting clients in finding suitable footwear solutions based on their preferences and needs.

Projects

Collaborative Content Creation Platform | HTML, CSS, Git

• This platform is used to create new content, edit existing content, send reports to creators, access the admin page, add new creators with admin privileges, and share content with others.

Test Automation Using Katalon Studio | Katalon Studio, Excel, Jenkins

Test all website functionalities using Katalon Studio. Create plans, test cases, test suites, test suite
collections, perform cross-browser testing, and execute command-line testing and ect.

Files Arrangement | Python, Git

• This Python script organizes files into different directories based on their types. It creates separate folders for images, music, videos, executables, archives, torrents, documents, code files, and design files.

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, SQL, HTML/CSS, OOPS

Frameworks: Bootstrap5

Software Testing: Manual Testing, Automation Testing, Jenkins, CI/CD

Developer Tools: Git, GitHub, VS Code, Debugging

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows